bridges in web free are very exposed and
often root causes of vulnerabilities if
you don't know yet what a bridge is then
don't worry because in this video mijo
from halborn will show us what a bridge
is and tell us about the vulnerability
in Aurora which was rewarded one million
dollars of bounty enjoy
hello mihau thank you so much for for
joining me again today we have a bug
that uses Aurora and my first question
is what Aurora even is and why do we use
it uh hi Greg thanks for having me here
again
um and to answer your question I
actually would like to show you a
diagram uh because I think it will it
will help us a lot uh but basically and
Aurora is
uh is an evm and that's how we call it
uh so it's an ethereum virtual machine
built on top of uh near smart contract
so imagine a regular virtual machine
um like um like like let's say Linux in
your virtualization software that runs
on your let's say Windows PC so it's a
computer running inside other computer
and you can say that that in case of
Aurora it works the same in the similar
manner you have an ethereum-like
execution layer ethereum like blockchain
running on top of the near and how it
works is like this
yeah how it works is uh like this
um that from the New Perspective it
actually uh Aurora is just another smart
contract uh but from Aurora's
perspective it's like completely uh
separate um chain it doesn't really know
um about the underlying infrastructure
that is the new protocol and the way it
works is that um when a user wants to
use Aurora then they create a regular
ethereum transaction the one that you
use on normal ethereum
and they send it to the RPC proxy which
wraps this ethereum into the new
transaction and sends this transaction
to um to Aurora smart contract
um in on the like new protocol uh layer
because ultimately
um it all needs every execution the hour
in the Aurora engine needs to be
initiated from uh from the near uh from
the near side from the New Perspective
and then the protocol unwraps this uh
the then the smart contract the aura
smart contract unwraps um this ethereum
transaction uh and execute it uh
executed in the context of of our engine
so if I have some money in if I have
some ease and I want to pay it to
someone who uses Aurora can I do it
uh yes you can but it's but not natively
natively those are two separate chains
however it is possible and that's where
bridges come from and here I have the
diagram I hope that that will represent
um
this concept the bridge is uh exactly
like it sounds it's it's a connection
between two two different environments
for them to uh to interact in case of uh
Aurora and there's this bridge is called
a Rainbow Bridge actually
and it's uh well there's always two
sides to it it needs to be on the near
side let's call it left and on the
ethereum side and let's call it right
um they have uh this uh very similar
contracts that are sort of related to
each other so you have the the bridges
themselves you have the connectors
um which would be quite important later
um and you have the connectors for
everything for anything you want so
erc20 connector you have a token and you
want the token to be transferred then
you have to have a connector for this
erc20 token on the left side and on the
right side for them to communicate if
you want to send
um either like you asked and then you
also need to have this ether connector
on the on the left side and on the right
side uh for them to to be able to
communicate
and how does the process look of
transferring something from from one
side to the other yeah and that's a
great question and those where I where
are their layers
um come from well one site needs to
let's say uh that uh I want to send
something from the left side to the
right side I need to execute some
transaction on the left side and we'll
go into that um in a bit
uh we need to execute this transaction
to let the left side know that we want
to initialize this transfer and then we
need to wait a little bit because those
layers are sort of a synchronization
Services
um between left and right side they will
after a little bit of time they will let
the other side know about new
transaction new blocks that that were
produced on the site so that the other
transaction so that the other side is
aware of them then on the one that's
done I will need to get a so-called
proof that it's for my transaction and I
don't need to like worry how to
construct it near near blockchain like
the near there's there's an API on the
near site
and for this to uh to get this
transaction uh sorry to get this proof
for this transaction and
um once I have that I go to the right
side to the ethereum and I use the uh
the connector that I want um that I'd
like to like complete my uh my transfer
because let's say I wanted to transfer
tokens so I used erc20 connector on the
left side I need to use the erc20
connector on the
um on the right side
I just provide my my proof and uh
because three layers shared the
information that about my transaction
before that the connector can verify
that it was actually my transaction is
legitimate it was me and they can just
send the tokens to me
so so do I understand this right there
is no
actual way to send money from one
blockchain to another but we sort of
destroy those tokens on one side and
then relayers or those synchronizers
tell the other blockchain that we've
burnt tokens on one side and we can now
use them on the other side yes exactly
sometimes it's not burning it's just
locking them that depends if the token
was breached or it's or it's native
essentially if it's native to the uh to
the blog to the given blockchain and you
want to send it then you just lock it
and if you already send a habit from
somewhere else and you want to send it
back then you burn it but yeah it's it's
exactly how you how you said that that's
how it works great so can we jump into
the code now
uh sure sure we can okay so uh here is
actually the if custodian contract which
is uh this connector but for the
ethereum
um Native asset this one is actually
um deployed on the
um on the ethereum side so the right in
our diagram that we that we've seen
before
and uh what's important here is this
withdraw function because this is what
was uh sort of problematic here
um what's important
um is that we need to when we want to
call it this is we sort of uh we are now
talking about it from the other uh other
way around this is the last step that we
would be taking
um in the whole process we need to
provide it with the proof data
um
and we pass and consume this proof this
function which is defined right here
well it makes sure that the proof is not
too old that that it's valid and that it
wasn't used before all sensible things
here but the most important thing here
is this require statement that makes
sure uh that uh the proof of whatever we
provided that this proof is related to
the transaction that were X that was
executed by something that's here called
near proof producer account and this is
actually the Aurora
um the Aurora smart contract so you need
to make sure that whatever you provide
here it was executed by the our smart
contract once that that's done
um you decode
um the result into something called burn
result which among other things contain
a field called it custodian and you need
to make sure that this this field
matches the address of this contract
that's executing this in ethereum site
to make sure that this is the connector
that is supposed to be completing the
the transaction and then if that's done
um then you basically just send ether to
to yourself
and where does the burn results come
from
uh yes uh well first let me show you how
it looks like in here because burn
result is actually quite simple
structure
um it contains the three Fields there's
amount which is just a number of tokens
that you would like to send recipient
which is the address that the tokens are
going to be sent to and the equestrian
address that I already mentioned and
there is actually
um a very similar structure on the
Aurora side let me show you yeah okay so
this is um this structure that's
reflected by this burn result it's
called with the result in the aura site
but as you can see it contains the same
information
you have the amount you have the
recipient ID and you have the if
custodian address
uh okay so now let's see uh where where
this um this with the result comes from
and
there is a function called a withdraw if
from near and this function is actually
returning this with the result let's see
what it does uh well of course it's it's
checked uh it checks authorization if
you um
if you are the owner or not if the
contract is paused and then it calls
internal withdraw is from near which is
an internal transaction we don't really
need to dive too much deep into it but
this uh I can tell you that this
function is basically just reducing your
ether
um balance on in the Aurora it's it's
burning those tokens and it's saving the
the state of the contract and then uh it
basically returns this withdrawal result
saying that this recipient address which
is
provided as one of the arguments because
you will be calling this function so you
want to specify who like to which
address those those tokens should should
go to
um then there's amount so whatever that
whatever amount that you are just burnt
on the on the other side and then
um the and the Aurora contract is
actually filling this each custodian
address uh by itself because
uh well it knows um it knows the the
connector on the other side so it can so
we don't need to provide it you you you
can just it will be specified on your
own now this withdrawal is from near is
not actually callable because this is
also an internal function but what is
callable is
function called withdraw here this is
the function that the user will actually
be calling to initialize this bridging
process in the in the uh on the left
side in the Aurora
as you can see right here it actually is
calling this withdraw it from near it
gets the result there's all this this
withdrawal result that we that we just
seen
and then it's converting them into the
stream of bytes and it converts it into
the output so the output of this whole
transaction is this um this structure
this withdrawal result structure just
serialized into into bytes
so to me it looks secure so far where's
the bug
let's look at
um at the back now yeah okay so just as
a summary for now we know that if we
want to withdraw the
uh the tokens on the ethereum side the
most important thing that we
um that we basically cannot go past is
that the executor ID needs to be this
new proof producer account so the
transaction had to be executed by the
Aurora contract on on the right side
sorry on the left side
um in the uh in the near in the new
blockchain
uh if that's the case then we'll have
our token transfer
and here is sort of a high level
overview of this process on the top you
have you can see the legitimate way of
um of doing this so you burn the
um the if on the near side you wait a
little bit so that
um this transaction is related to the to
the to the ethereum
and then you
um then this one that's done then the
so-called light client those have
different names but those basically are
those three layers that share this um at
this information uh we'll know about it
then you will be able to receive proof
and with this proof you can call you can
complete the whole process in the if
connector which is just if custodian
um and contract that we looked uh looked
at before and now uh
um now in the bottom there's
um a vulnerable version of this process
and as you can see
the ethereum site remains exactly the
same and yeah also I struggled to find
the difference between these two at
first yes and that's because the only
thing that's that's changed is how you
initialize the process as you can see
normally you need to burn if and you do
it by calling this withdraw function and
it turns out that it's possible to make
the Aurora produce the same output as
though you would burn in Burn The Ether
but without actually burning it you can
do it by calling a view function of a
Eco contract
that will be sort of an exploit for all
of this process uh so how does this look
is this is this contract even related to
this whole flow it wasn't used normally
was it uh let me show you actually I
have this contract prepared right here
um you should you should see the the Eco
contract and I know that it's all very
well overwhelmingly
um short so
uh this is the the expert contract yes
this is the exploit contract and it
doesn't mean you could steal with those
12 13 lines yeah um there was uh about
uh 50
000 ether uh stored in this um
in this if custodian contract and every
single one of this ether was vulnerable
was susceptible to this to the
vulnerability that could be it could be
stolen and at that time
um with the if price uh uh in that day
it was about 63 million dollars
wow but it's it's looks complex with
this assembly function what do they mean
yeah so all this contract does is takes
whatever input the user provided and
then outputs it almost in exactly the
same manner there are some changes but
they are related to the evm
internals of how this is processed and
it's not actually very important for
this for this to understand this exploit
yeah yeah I guess it's it's probably a
typical thing where for the exploiter
it's quite natural and then when you
read the write-up it looks like crazy
operations but but they're actually yeah
yeah exactly but how would we call this
with what argument uh sure so um let me
show you the Aurora code
so we know that there is this withdrawal
function but there is also a view
function defined
[Music]
which is intended to call view function
in the um in the Aurora contracts
because our eyes and evm you can deploy
any contract there that's totally legit
and that's the way it's supposed to be
actually working
um
and you you may need to want to
um you want to call those functions so
what you do here to initialize the the
exploit you deploy your own contract
which is this Eco contract that we just
seen and then you call the view function
with a specific argument what are the
arguments the arguments um well as you
can see as as you remember the Eco
contract will basically just return
whatever we uh we will send to it so we
need to make it look like it's going to
return return as something that will
look like a burn result and now if we
read through this now we have we have
this arguments here that are provided by
the user and we are calling a function
called view with args which is defined
right here it's just a wrapper for
another function that's called View and
view is actually right here
uh we get the parameters we are calling
the um we are calling the
um the the specific function that we
want to call and then we have we get
some result which as you can see here I
hope you can see it well uh it's a
vector of
um of unsigned uh well numbers of eight
uh bits uh length which is basically a
byte so this is just a byte string
and then you convert it into the result
and return it like so
now I uh I hope that you are still uh
remember this we throw it from near
function because it also only returns
this structure
which is then in the withdraw function
right here
convert it into bytes and you return the
bytes
so
if you have your uh Eco contract
deployed in the Aurora you can just
provide
um a specific string of bytes
that will look like
um that when they will be deserialized
into this uh this burn result structure
they will look like something that makes
sense so what you need to provide is
some bytes that will represent the
number of tokens you want to send then
bytes that will represent the um that
will represent the address of the
recipient so probably your own address
in ethereum
and then you will need to also provide
um
address for the custodian so that when
sorry so that when this um when this
structure is deserialized
um it's the the custodian contract would
be able to verify that
um that it is supposed to be actually
executing this this transaction this is
the connector we want but if custodian
address it's a public knowledge you know
it so there is absolutely no problem in
you uh just sending this transaction and
receiving it and receiving the output
and what you need to do then is just
wait because this is the only difference
in the whole process then you're waiting
for the
uh for the whole
um for this layers to to let know the
other side uh in this case the right
side the ethereum site
um about the transaction then you need
to get the proof but there's no reason
you wouldn't get any uh you don't need
to worry about it because this is a
legitimate transaction that and that
happened
um in the Aurora so you get this proof
as as any other via the API and then you
send it to the if custodian
which will deserialize everything and
with it this will result in the
successful transaction and you would be
able to withdraw ether not uh anything
any amount that you want because there's
some limitations to it
um for the maximum number but then you
can just keep executing this transaction
and slowly drain the ethodian contract
from it so to sum up and confirm I
understand correctly we need two things
for for this transaction to happen we
need the withdraw function
output from the withdraw function to
have a proper structure and we need this
to be a trusted contract address but the
view function allows us to Output pretty
much whatever we want so we can use this
structure and it's the same address so
this is also taken care of and the rest
of the transaction is legit is that
right exactly yes that's exactly how it
is so amazing amazing bug with so much
money to be to be stolen great
um it wasn't exploded in the wild was it
oh no no it wasn't uh thankfully it was
um it was reported to the Aurora team
and they could could fix it I can
actually show you the fixed word because
it's it's actually quite interesting
okay
uh and the fix was in the 2.6
twine
uh
well basically the Aurora team added the
return output function which parse which
parses the output of the whatever
transaction that's that happened it's
for example in the view transaction and
then it checks uh for the length of this
value and what this value is and if the
length is at least 56 bytes long and
those range of bytes is the custodian
address that is known uh then uh the
chances are that this is an exploit for
this vulnerability so so basically the
contract just panics and says that it's
illegal return and as far as I can tell
uh it's still it looks like a just a hot
fix for this vulnerability but it's
still there and this is how it's how
it's fixed I I don't think it was
um there is something else implemented
as of right now at least
okay that's that's funny thank you so
much for for joining us and explaining
uh the box to ask me how thank you so
much for having me
if you enjoyed this video check out this
one that's on your screen at the moment
about an input validation bug also in
Aurora and also rewarded one million
dollars for now thank you for watching
and goodbye